

José Ramón Ibarra Cisneros

Email address: jose.ibarra18@tectijuana.edu.mx

Phone number: +52 664 480 1698

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jos%C3%A9-ibarra-4b03b81ba/

Location: Tijuana. Baja California. México

### About me

I am an Industrial Engineer with Software development skills and 3 years of experience in the manufacturing industry. I am currently looking for a transition to the IT sector, I have knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, SQL (SQLite), GIT, GitHub and Vercel pages management. My main goal is to continue learning about Software Development technologies and be able to develop and grow in a company in which I can contribute significantly with my knowledge and skills.

#### **Technical Skills**

Proficient:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Basic:

ReactJS, SQL.

Other Skills:

Git, GitHub, Vercel.

# **Work Experience**

### Process Engineer, Sumitronics | Nov 2021 - Feb 2023

- Designated to various production lines as process engineer.
- Project management to increase capacity and reduce personnel in production lines.
- Implementation of improvements based on the kaizen philosophy, such as redesign of stations to avoid defects, improve ergonomics and improve productivity, redistribution of WIP areas on the production floor to avoid waste like overproduction, transfers, unnecessary movements, over-inventory and to improve material flow.
- Process flow design for new production lines and reworks.
- Process redesign, creation and updating of work instructions.
- Evaluation and validation of new tools for manufacturing processes.
- Evaluation and validation of new manufacturing processes through tests involving different variables.

#### Manufacturing Technician, Jabil Healthcare | Dec 2020 - Nov 2021

- Packing area supervisor.
- Manage and coordinate packing personnel and resources of the different accounts to keep the lines running and avoid downtime or line stoppages. (Supervision of 26 employees).
- Constant communication and teamwork with different departments (quality, planning, materials and health and safety) to avoid problems that could affect production and the product quality.
- Follow up to the action plans of the different manufacturing areas.
- Implementation and follow up of 5's in all manufacturing areas.
- Leader and participant in the development and implementation of kaizen ideas focused on Lean Manufacturing.

## Continuous Improvement Intern, Katzkin | Feb 2020 – Dec 2020

- Responsible of continuous improvement.
- MDI process development and supervision (standard work, DAP, handling of abnormalities and visual controls).
- Kaizen and VSM events participation.
- Participation in the development of a quality control plan.

## Lenguages

Spanish: Native proficiency. English: conversational level.

## Soft Skills

Ability to work in team, ability to work under pressure, fast learner, problem solver, accountability, organized, punctual, proactive, analytical, good communication skills (oral and written).

#### Education

Bachelor's Degree in Industrial Engineering, ITT.